Bjørn Tore Svinningen

Heliveien 945, 1820 Spydeberg, Norway

Phone: +47 90516604

Mail: postmannen@gmail.com | twitter: twitter.com/erter1 | github: github.com/postmannen |

linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/bj%C3%B8rn-tore-svinningen-1394816/

Summary

A highly skilled professional with a passion for knowledge and a keen interest in exploring various fields such as programming, networks, security, Linux, psychology, music, electronics, farming, and more. In 2017, I decided to focus on Go development as the primary area of expertise. My multidisciplinary background often provides me with the unique ability to tackle challenges from diverse angles, making me an effective contributor to successful product development and adept at solving intricate problems within projects or independently.

Professional Experience

Been working with Data centers, Network, Security, Servers, and Monitoring since 1997, and made the switch to fulltime Development in 2017.

Creator of **ctrl** a fleet manager service.

Doc: postmannen.github.io/ctrl/

Github: github.com/postmannen/ctrl

The most recent jobs and activities can be found below.

2024 - Present, Ikomm, Senior Security Engineer

• Go Programming. Design and Build Security Platforms.

2020 - 2023, Raa Labs, Contract

- Build an Edge Cloud infrastructure/platform from the ground up for ships sailing around the globe.
- Create an event driven infrastructure controller, Steward for RaaLabs

- Kubernetes on the Edge with K3s.
- Created various tools for modudbus, Linux and automation services, where most are opensourced with an MIT license and can be found at Raalabs's Github

2017 - 2019, Study programming

Go, Software Architecture.

2004 - Present, Self Employee, Freelance

- Go / Golang Development.
- · Automation and orchestration.
- Network and server monitoring.
- Network lan / wan & security.
- Linux systems.
- IOT

2013 - 2017, Datametrix AS, Senior Network Consultant

- Building a cloud platform from scratch for the Norwegian market
- Network/Security architecture done with Cisco, Checkpoint and F5 on Datametrix's Cloud provider network.
- Network and services monitoring based on Centreon/Nagios.
- Automation and orchestration of cloud services
- Scripting/Programming in Perl and JavaScript.
- Design and implementation of Monitoring platform counting 40k+ monitored services.

2012 - 2013, IPsoft, Senior Network Consultant

- Senior Network Consultant.
- Technical Project Lead.
- Monitoring and Automation.

2008 - 2012, Steria AS, Senior Network Consultant

- Network Design, implementation and management.
- Implementation projects of large and smaller customers: Planning, migration, customer relationship.
- Maintenance of Steria's datacenter's based on Cisco hardware.

· Network monitoring based on Centreon/Nagios.

2004 - 2008, Nortura, Senior Network Consultant

- Responsible for Lan/Wan, Security.
- Maintainance and implementation of Linux and Windows servers.
- System monitoring based on Centreon/Nagios and other monitoring tools available on the Linux platform.

2004 - 2004, Systeam, System Consultant

• Maintainance of customer network, servers and computers.

1997 - 2003, Telenor Mobil, System Consultant

- Network and server maintenance.
- · 2nd line Customer support.

Technical Experience

I like to know how technology and the value chain work as a whole. Other areas where i have good experience are:

- Operating systems with services: Linux and Windows.
- Monitoring systems.
- Logging systems.

Industries and verticals

- IT Data Center, Service Provider and Cloud.
- Telecom.
- Farming and food production.
- Shipping.
- Municipalities.

My Side Project

I find great interest in Drones, IOT, and Code to get better control and results in agriculture.
Based on an idea I have about making drones and AI available for small farmers as well as big,

I've been working on a driver/controller for Parrot drones from scratch where the end goal is the help farmers get better insight in the status of the crops on the fields. parrot driver in Go.

Open Source

• All my code and learning material are put available on Github. Hopefully for others to use, learn from, or for detecting issues in the code I have yet to know of.

Some more examples of my projects and ideas are mentioned below

- Async management of servers/endpoints using Nats where everything is done with passing messages and concurrent. Steward
- CTRL, async fleet manager. The original repository of Steward were made private, and CTRL is the continuation of honing that idea on my own CTRL.
- Traffic sniffer who lets you know what your computer communicated with, and how much data transfered, trafficmonitor
- Driver for Parrot drones. parrot
- My repository from when I started with Go, for learning and testing out ideas and concepts, golearning

Things I plan to look more into in the future

- Use of Go with embedded devices and micro controllers.
- Read and analyze Network Data with Go.

Education

1991-1995, Electronics, Certificate Of Apprenticeship

 1991-1995 Electronics, Computer Technical/Hardware, Micro controllers, Pascal, ASM, Audio/Video.

Languages

- Norwegian (native speaker)
- English